Noah Saldaña

bbsaldana90@gmail.com 617-880-9433 github.com/saldanan1

Front-End Developer & Designer

Accomplished software engineer with BS Degree in Computer Science and demonstrated strengths designing, prototyping, and releasing successful digital products in the Mobile, Web, and Game Development space. Highly committed to the use of Design Thinking, Customer Experience (CX), and Human Centered Design (HCD) principles. Recognized consistently for an extremely adaptable and curious mindset, combined with a highly motivated, team-focused, and accountable work style.

Education

Washington University in St. Louis BS in Computer Science, May 2020

Skills

Computer Science

JavaScript | Swift | Node.JS | SQL | HTML Stimulus | Ruby | MongoDB | React | CSS Discord.JS | Tailwind

Design

Design Thinking | Human-Centered Design | Iteration | Storyboarding Data Visualization

Tools

Unity | Fusion360 | XCode | Rhino Pruse3D | Laser Cutting | Git | MySQL 3D Printing | Arudino AR | MongoDB

Awards

Core77: Social Impact Award

bit.ly/Core77Award

Award won for the Skills Vest: a vest aimed at helping children with Cerebral Palsy to practice their fine motor skills. Served as Designer, Tester, and Inventor of this innovative new wearable technology.



noahsaldanadesign.com

Work Experience

Front End Developer

Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

Nuvu Studios

- Serve as a web developer for this innovative Education company, helping create an in-house portfolio- based website allowing for the documentation of all student projects and work product.
- Gathered requirements and leveraged client, student, and partner feedback to model the website to specific user needs.
- Handled a diverse mix of website design and development responsibilities, as well as updating the site on an ongoing basis with new features, bug fixes, and improvements.
- · Stack: Javascript, Ruby, Stimulus, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Tailwind

Oracle Discord Bot

bit.ly/DiscordEloBot

May 2020 - Present

- Identified faults in currently used "ratings" tracking chat bot on Magic the Gathering Discord Servers.
- Created agile and adaptive bot focused on maximizing user experience.
- Learned Node.JS, MongoDB and Discord.JS to begin groundwork for an open sourced project.
- After initial release, worked to create a second version to adhere to newly updated Discord.JS practices.

Playing With Power

Dec 2021 - Present

YouTube Channel

- Worked with this premiere MTG Content Creator and developed biweekly gameplay videos, podcasts and host tournaments for over 80,000 YouTube subscribers.
- Spearheaded Live Streaming presence. Created resources, booked guests and scheduled weekly streams for hundreds of viewers.
- Learned valuable script writing, team building and management skills.

Web Developer (Contract Role)

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

Solar United Neighbors

- Worked with clients to update and create content on outdated website.
- Refactored and rebuilt existing structure into a more cohesive and updated format.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, WordPress.